(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T23:14:40.891011",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
君に 逢いたい時だって
Even when I want to see you,
どこか 逢えない気持ちがある
deep down I feel like I can't.
だけど 本当の優しさが
But true kindness
そこに あるかも知れない
might be right there.
人込みに 揺られている
Swayed by the crowd,
どこかに 宛てがあるわけじゃない
it's not like I have anywhere to go.
独りきり 歩いても
Even if I walk all alone,
何か 解決することじゃない
it won't solve anything.
自分が 本当に望んでる
What I truly desire...
気持ちは きっと
...is a feeling that surely means...
これから 二人で
...walking forward together...
歩いて行くことさ
...from now on.
君に 逢いたい時だって
Even when I want to see you,
どこか 逢えない気持ちがある
deep down I feel like I can't.
だけど本当の優しさが
But true kindness
そこに あるかも知れない
might be right there.
二人 輝いた季節は
The season we sparkled together
きっと これからも続いてく
will surely keep continuing from now on.
だから 大切な未来に
So, into our precious future,
この想いを 残したい
I want to leave these feelings behind.
飽きるまで 話しても
Even if we talk until we're tired,
全部 分かり合えるわけじゃない
it doesn't mean we'll understand everything.
言葉より 伝えたい
Words can't fully express...
気持ちが この胸にあふれてる
...the feelings overflowing in my heart.
君がいつか 探した夢の
The continuation of the dream you once sought...
続きは きっと
...let's surely...
二人で 描いて行こう
...draw it together as two.
忘れないで
Please don't forget.
独りきり 孤独なようで
Though it feels like we're alone in solitude,
皆 何かに悩んでいる
everyone is troubling over something.
すぐには 変わらないけれど
Things won't change right away,
とにかく 信じていたい
but I just want to keep believing.
流した 涙拭き去って
Wiping away the shed tears,
ずっと 君のそばで生きたい
I want to live by your side forever.
いつか 振り返った時に
Because when I look back someday,
後悔 したくないから
I don't want to have any regrets.
君に...
To you...
会いたいと言いたくて
I want to tell you that I want to see you
二人 輝いた季節は
The season when the two of us shone...
後悔したくないから
Because I don't want to have any regrets
叶わない 夢なんて
A dream that won't come true...
簡単に 口にはしたくない
I don't want to speak of it so easily
諦めた 瞬間（とき）に
The moment you give up,
自分自身 終わらせてるだけ
you're just putting an end to yourself.
もっと 単純に感じたい
I want to feel things more simply.
君のこと いつも
About you, always...
素直に 笑うよ
I'll smile honestly.
未来は 続いてく
The future goes on.
君が ホントに スキだって
That I really like you,
いつも 心に飾ってたい
I always want to keep that in my heart.
楽しさだけが 全てなら
If fun is all there is,
本当の 愛じゃないから
then it isn't real love.
君に...
To you...
会いたいと言いたくて
I want to tell you that I want to see you.
二人 輝いた季節は きっと これからも続いてく
The season when the two of us shone will surely continue from now on.
だから 大切な未来に この想いを残したい
So, I want to leave these feelings for our precious future.
君に...
To you...
会いたいと言いたくて
I want to tell you that I want to see you.
二人 輝いた季節は...
The season when the two of us shone...
みんな6周年ライブに来てくれてアリぺコ！
Everyone, thanks for coming to my 6th anniversary live, peko!
そして大変お待たせしました！
And sorry to keep you waiting for so long!
そうそう！そうそう！
Right, right! Right, right!
けどね、みんなに楽しんでもらえるようなライブになってるぺコだから、ぜひともお楽しみに！
But you know, it's going to be a live concert everyone can enjoy, so please look forward to it!
そして1曲目は「そこにあるかも知れない…」を歌わせてもらったぺコ！
And for the first song, I sang "Soko ni Aru Kamo Shirenai..." peko!
ま、っていうことは今回のテーマは…そう！パチスロ第2弾！
Which means this time's theme is... yes! Pachislot Part 2!
当たり演出もね、めちゃめちゃいろいろありますんで、ぜひとも次の曲は何が来るかなって考えながら楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいぺコ！
There are all kinds of jackpot effects, so I hope you'll enjoy guessing what the next song will be!
そして、今回のハッシュタグはこちら！
And the hashtag for today is right here!
「#兎田ぺこら6周年記念LIVE」ぺコなので、たくさんポストしてください！
It's #UsadaPekora6thAnniversaryLIVE peko, so please post a lot!
ちゅうわけで、そんじゃ早速回していくか！
So with that said, let me spin the reels right away!
よいしょ！あれ？
Heave-ho! Huh?
お！
Oh!
あ、始まった！
Ah, it started!
運命の一撃
A strike of fate!
好機 好機 好機
Chance! Chance! Chance!
笑うべきだと分かった時は 泣くべきじゃねえぺこ！
When you know you should laugh, you shouldn't cry, peko!
運命の一撃を叩き込め！
Strike with the blow of fate!
咲かすか 枯らすか 現在
Whether to make it bloom or wither now,
燃えるように 日が沈む
as if burning, the sun sets.
歯車が回る
The gears turn.
ラッパが鳴れば チャッカ サマザマな 楽しの物語
When the trumpet sounds, igniting various enjoyable stories.
発車 ガラガラ トッシャ ガラガラ
Departures clattering, arrivals rattling.
真っ赤な過去が多い 影る 道化師の笑み
Shadowed by a crimson past, a clown's smile...
仮面の裏側
Behind the mask.
どんなに消しても消えない 傷を抱いたんだとしても
Even if bearing wounds that can never be erased no matter how much you try,
咲かすか 枯らすか 現在
whether to make it bloom or wither now,
燃えるように 日が沈む
as if burning, the sun sets.
真夜中の暗い 孤独から
From the dark solitude of midnight,
繰り出す
reaching out.
微かな 響く鐘が
A faintly ringing bell...
陰る日々の 道標
A signpost through shadowy days,
音の鳴る先へ
towards where the sound leads.
ラッパが鳴れば チャッカ ワラワラ マッカな幕の真ん中
When the trumpet sounds, igniting giggles in the middle of a crimson curtain.
はまだかまさか さかさまのまま 紡ぐ論理
Is it not yet? No way, spinning logic while upside down.
足を掴まれ 奈落の底まで
Grabbed by the feet down to the bottom of the abyss.
脚色も忘れて 息もできない
Forgetting dramatization, unable to even breathe.
咲かすか 枯らすか 現在
Whether to make it bloom or wither now,
眠るように 目を閉じる
closing eyes as if falling asleep.
身体中巡る 猛毒から
From the deadly poison circulating through the body,
逃げ出す
escaping.
微かな 響く鐘に
To the faintly ringing bell,
耳を澄ませ 生きるのか
listen closely—will I live?
どちらか選べ
Choose one or the other.
さあ
Now!
快感も 罰ゲームのように 未来だけ 想えばいい
Even pleasure is like a punishment game; just think of the future.
過去の亡霊を 消してー！
Erase the ghosts of the past!
咲かすか 枯らすか 現在
Whether to make it bloom or wither now,
燃えるように 日が沈む
as if burning, the sun sets.
真夜中の深い 孤独から
From the deep solitude of midnight,
繰り出す
reaching out.
運命が 壊れるような 声で叫べ
Shout in a voice that seems to shatter fate!
始まりの合図 幕開け さあ 舞って踊れ
The signal to begin, the curtain rises! Come on, dance and spin!
誰しも 最期には 涙流す
Everyone sheds tears at the very end.
だから今は こらえ進む
So for now, endure and move forward.
幕が下りる その時まで まだ
Until the curtain falls, not yet.
絶えず 歯車が回る
Endlessly, the gears turn.
究極Vモンキー！
Ultimate V-Monkey!
何かをするのに
To do something...
理由なんか要らないね
We don't need any reason, do we?
熱くなるよ
It's getting hot,
君を見ているだけで
just by looking at you.
戦っているのよ
I am fighting.
期待はどんな時でも
Expectations, no matter when,
もつれて 迷い込む
get tangled up and stray.
イチカバチカ
All or nothing,
夢に向かい加速する
accelerating towards the dream.
ココロが止まらない
My heart won't stop.
感じてる
I can feel it.
悩み多き日常のターンに
In this turn of daily life full of worries,
君といる時の自分が一番好きだよ
I like myself best when I'm with you.
ココロは止まらない
My heart won't stop.
光の中
In the middle of the light,
七色の水ふぶきあげて
splashing a rainbow spray of water,
新しい明日の風に向かい 走り出そうよ
let's start running toward the wind of a new tomorrow.
二人きりで
Just the two of us.
会いたい気持ちが
My desire to see you
ため息に溶けていく
melts away into a sigh.
寂しい夜はそばにいてくれた
You stayed by my side on lonely nights.
泣き出しそうになった時
When I was about to burst into tears,
気づかないふりしてくれたね
you pretended not to notice.
重ねる唇から
From our overlapping lips,
こぼれる切なさも愛しさも
both sadness and affection overflow.
ココロが止まらない
My heart won't stop.
感じてる
I can feel it.
もっと全ても変えてみたい
I want to change everything even more.
願った奇跡がこんなにも近くにあったよ
The miracle I wished for was right here so close to me.
ココロは止まらない
My heart won't stop.
通り過ぎた
Having passed by,
夏のにおい懐かしいね
the scent of summer feels so nostalgic.
君を好きになってから前より寂しがり屋に
Since I fell for you, I've become lonelier than before,
なってしまった
I have become.
こわいものはたった一つ
There's only one thing that scares me:
君が優しすぎること
that you are far too kind.
たそがれが風止めても
Even if twilight stops the wind,
夢へのブレーキかからない
there's no braking on the way to my dream.
ココロが止まらない
My heart won't stop.
感じてる
I can feel it.
きっと答えは一つじゃない
Surely there isn't just one answer.
君に会うためだけにとても優しくなれるよ
Just to meet you, I can become so gentle.
ココロは止まらない
My heart won't stop.
月の雫
Drops of the moon,
ずっと君を探してた
I was searching for you all this time.
同じ時 同じ星見上げてこのままきっと
Looking up at the same star at the same time, surely just like this,
色あせぬように
so it will never fade away.
リーチ！
Reach!
輝く マリンブルー
Shining marine blue,
やっと出会えた サマータイム
summertime we finally met!
ミラクル マリンパワー
Miracle marine power,
「せーの」で飛び込もう！
let's dive in on "Ready, go!"
Go! Go! Let's Go!
SEA STORY
太陽さんさん 裸足で 駆け出していこう ビーチへ
Bright sunshine, barefoot, let's run out to the beach!
常夏冒険 見つけにいこう 海のワンダーランド
Let's go find an everlasting summer adventure in the ocean wonderland!
みんな歌えば
If everyone sings,
イルカがジャンプ
dolphins will jump high,
カニとタコのダンス
crabs and octopuses will dance!
スペシャルな夢を描こう！
Let's paint a special dream!
輝くマリンブルー やっと出会ったサマータイム
Shining marine blue, summer time has finally come!
ミラクルマリンパワー 「せーの」で飛び込もう！
Miracle marine power, let's dive in on "ready, set, go!"
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY!
海底探検 泳いで 一緒に遊びにいこうよ
Undersea exploration, swimming along, let's go play together!
笑顔が何よりの たったひとつの宝物だよ
Your smile is the single greatest treasure of all.
シャチの背中に
Riding on the killer whale's back,
サンゴのトンネル
through the coral tunnel,
クラゲのリズム
to the rhythm of the jellyfish,
始まる夢のステージ！
the stage of dreams begins!
きらめくマリンスノー
Sparkling marine snow,
みんな一緒に Everyday
everyone together every day,
スペシャルサマーソング
a special summer song,
「せーの」で始めよう！
let's start on "ready, set, go!"
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY!
輝くマリンブルー やっと出会ったサマータイム
Shining marine blue, summer time has finally come!
ミラクルマリンパワー 「せーの」で飛び込もう！
Miracle marine power, let's dive in on "ready, set, go!"
グレートマリンブルー 水平線の彼方まで
Great marine blue, all the way beyond the horizon!
ミラクルマリンパワー 「せーの」で飛び込もう！
Miracle marine power, let's dive in on "ready, set, go!"
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY!
ルパン三世のテーマ
[Theme of Lupin III]
真っ赤な薔薇は あいつの唇
Bright red roses are her lips,
やさしく抱きしめて くれとねだる
begging you to hug her gently.
瞳の奥に 獲物を映して
Reflecting her prey deep in her eyes,
寂しく問いかける 愛の在りか
she lonely asks where love lies.
男には 自分の世界がある たとえるなら
Men have their own worlds. If I were to compare it,
空をかける ひとすじの流れ星
it's like a single shooting star streaking across the sky.
孤独な笑みを 夕陽にさらして
Exposing a lonely smile to the setting sun...
背中で泣いてる 男の美学
Crying behind his back, that's a man's aesthetic.
真珠の色は あいつのまなざし
The color of pearls is in that look in her eyes,
遥かな幸せを 夢に描く
picturing distant happiness in a dream.
いためることを 恐れるあまりに
So afraid of hurting someone,
冷たく突き放す 愛もあるさ
there is a love that pushes them away coldly.
男には 自分の世界がある たとえるなら
A man has his own world; if you were to compare it,
風をはらい 荒くるう稲光
it's raging lightning that parts the wind.
都会の闇に 体を溶かして
Melting his body into the urban darkness,
口笛吹いてる 男の美学
whistling away—that is a man's aesthetic.
乙女アタック 突入!
Entering Otome Attack!
いざ勝負!
Now, let's battle!
いくペコ！
Let's go, peko!
いざ勝負!
Now, let's battle!
楽勝ペコ！
Easy win, peko!
夜を彷徨う影が 光を裂こうと吠える
Shadows wandering the night howl, seeking to tear apart the light.
罪深き羊達 ひれ伏しなさい 容赦はしません
Sinful sheep, prostrate yourselves, we will show no mercy.
守るべき人のため 正義のため 優しい心 優しい愛のために
For the ones we must protect, for justice, for a gentle heart and gentle love.
どんなに傷つこうと 祈りましょう 御意に！ 誓う命かけて 捷路を！ 戰場、翔けて
No matter how injured we get, let us pray! Staking our lives, soaring across the battlefield!
信じた仲間たちと
Together with the comrades we believe in,
この手に宿る力 信じて
believing in the power dwelling in these hands.
狂い咲けよ
Bloom madly!
咲き誇れ 同志の華よ
Bloom in pride, blossom of comrades!
戦の地に降り立つ夢
A dream landing on the battlefield
運命を 大輪の炎 闇を蹴散らして
Scatter the darkness with great flames of destiny,
勝利を 勇気と熱を糧に 掴め
And seize victory with courage and passion as your fuel!
連れて行こう 辿り着く金色の空 笑顔を育む大地へ
Let's take you to the golden sky we reach, to the land that nurtures smiles!
夜はいずれ去り 朝が訪れる
Night will eventually pass, and morning will arrive.
全てを越えて 君の愛 叶う
Beyond everything, your love will come true!
星の巡りを辿り 手にした希望の十字
Tracing the orbit of the stars, holding the cross of hope in hand.
後悔などしないわ 救いは私が与える
I have no regrets; salvation is what I shall bestow!
発条仕掛けの憂鬱 踊れ影よ 光が弾きし舞 遊戯はおしまい
Clockwork gloom, dance o shadows! Light-bursting dance, the game is over!
大胆無敵な技 目指す場所は 勝利の扉開く艶 命生まれる楽園
Daring and invincible techniques, the destination is the glory opening the door to victory, a paradise where life is born.
さぁ 共に行きましょう
Now, let us go together!
正義は必ず勝つ いつでも
Justice will always prevail, forever!
空を渡る 溢れだし燃える想いが 鮮やかに彩る虹へ
Crossing the sky, overflowing burning feelings reach into a vividly colored rainbow.
伸ばす手と手 瞳を交わして絆を結べば 見えてくる新しい朝が
Reaching hand to hand, meeting eyes, tying bonds reveals a new morning...
時を超えて 暁の幸せはほら 誰の上にも降り注ぐ
Transcending time, look, the dawn's happiness pours down upon everyone!
胸の中を 雨はやがて止み 渇きを癒すよ
Inside the heart, the rain will soon stop, healing the thirst.
過去を解き放て 君の夢を問う
Release the past, ask of your dream!
貴方と想いを 数えきれないほどの出会いと別れ 重ねて
Overlapping thoughts with you, through countless encounters and partings...
真実 人は生きる意味を見つける
Truly, people find the meaning of life.
狂い咲けよ 咲き誇れ 同志の華よ
Bloom madly! Bloom in pride, flower of comrades!
戦の地に降り立つ夢
A dream landing on the battlefield
運命を 大輪の炎 闇を蹴散らして
Scatter the darkness with great flames of destiny,
勝利を 勇気と熱を糧に 掴め
And seize victory with courage and passion as your fuel!
連れて行こう 辿り着く金色の空 笑顔を育む大地へ
Let's take you to the golden sky we reach, to the land that nurtures smiles!
祝福が 夜はいずれ去り 朝が訪れる
Blessings come as the night eventually leaves and morning arrives.
全てを越えて 君の愛 叶う
Transcending everything, your love will come true!
待っていたぞ、ペコーラ
I've been waiting for you, Pekora.
バトルボーナス GET!
Battle Bonus GET!
Welcome to this crazy Time このイカれた時代へようこそ君は
Welcome to this crazy time! Welcome to this crazy era, you are...
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
まともな奴ほど feel so bad 正気でいられるなんて運がいいぜ you
The saner you are, the worse it feels; you're lucky to stay sane, you!
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
時はまさに世紀末 澱んだ街角で僕らは出会った
The time is truly the end of the century, we met at a stagnant street corner.
Keep you burning 駆け抜けて この腐敗と自由と暴力のまっただなか
Keep you burning, run through the thick of this corruption, freedom, and violence!
No boy no cry 悲しみは 絶望じゃなくて明日のマニフェスト
No boy, no cry, sadness isn't despair, but a manifesto for tomorrow!
We are living, living in the eighties
We still fight, fighting in the eighties
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi!
どこもしこも傷だらけ
Covered in scars everywhere,
うずくまって泣いてては始まらないから
crouching down and crying won't get us anywhere.
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
どっちを向いても feel so sad
Whichever way I turn, I feel so sad,
だけど死には至らない
but it won't kill me.
気分はどうだい？
How are you feeling?
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
ここは永遠のロックランド
This is the eternal rockland.
拳を握りしめ僕らは出会った
Clenching our fists, we met.
Keep you burning 駆け抜けて
Keep you burning, running through.
この狂気と希望と幻滅のまっただなか
In the midst of this madness, hope, and disillusionment.
No boy no cry 進まなきゃ
No boy, no cry, we must push forward
勢いを増した向かい風の中を
through the headwinds that have gathered strength.
We are living, living in the eighties
We still fight, fighting in the eighties
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi!
野うさぎ討伐戦 突入！
Nousagi Suppression Battle! Commencing!
お前の相手は超うさぎが買って出るペコ！
I, Super Usagi, will step up to take you on, peko!
PUSHペコ！
Push, peko!
ごちそうさでした！
Thank you for the feast!
完全撃破
[Complete Annihilation]
This is a fate that brought us here, watch my long shot
Feel like I am falling into the flame of lies
Tell me what do you want from me
Trying not to step back to where I used to belong
Looking for the escape from pain
I will cross my fingers hoping not to be sacrificed
約束したんだ 君とその希望に
I promised you and that hope.
Get in the raid, get ready for the time to come
浮かび上がるシルエット追いかけ
Chasing the emerging silhouette,
Drop down the reason why I'm standing here alone
Maybe it's already too late to regain
運命としてかかげた灯を失くさないで
Don't lose the light held up as fate.
What if I could right my wrongs and save you from the pain
It's not enough it's not enough for me to break the rule upon this world
I will never gonna leave you, never wanna lose you
I'm never gonna leave you, never wanna lose you.
We'll make it in the end
Not backing down for real
I won't trace someone else's life
I know who I am
Blame me if I'm not the fairy thing
Take the risk of everything
Justify this cruel world
悲しみに浸された 叫びどこへ
Where do the screams steeped in sadness go?
吸い込まれていく 影を残して
Sucked away, leaving behind a shadow...
I will cross my fingers hoping not to be sacrificed
いつのまにか 君とのその希望が力に
Before I knew it, that hope with you turned into strength
Get in line and get ready for the time to come
浮かび上がる 自由へと 追いかけて
Chasing after the freedom that emerges
Make the choice
Enjoy and recreate yourself, it's all you
何度だって
No matter how many times,
いいんだ 覚悟して
it's fine, prepare yourself
んだ 全て
...everything
守ると決めたよ
I've decided to protect it all
君がいるから
because you are here
絡み合う
Intertwining
未来を
futures,
この手で
with these hands
変えてみせるとして
I'll show you I can change them
すべきことは
What needs to be done,
分かっているから
I already know
Take this pain away from me この胸の
Take this pain away from me, onto this heart's
鼓動に乗せて
beating rhythm
There's no way I can fail 見届けて
There's no way I can fail, watch over me
ほしいと 願った
as I wished
強欲だ
[Visual: Greed]
超強欲 BONUS
[Visual: Super Greed BONUS]
So tell the reason why I'm standing here alone
Maybe it's already too late to regain
運命として掲げた火を なくさないで
Don't extinguish the flame held up as fate
Brace yourself don't forget this is your fate
What if I could right my wrongs and save you from the pain
It's not enough
It's not enough for me to break
the rule upon this world
I will never gonna leave you, never wanna lose you, I'll make it in the end
Not backing down for real
I will chase someone else's life
I know who I am
待っていたのはこの瞬間
[Visual: What I was waiting for was this moment]
待っていたのはこの瞬間！
What I was waiting for was this moment!
BONUS確定ペコ！
BONUS CONFIRMED, PEKO!
錬金術師をなめるなよ！ 一撃で...
[Visual: Don't underestimate an alchemist! In one strike...]
虹色のフリューゲル
[Title: Rainbow-Colored Flügel]
Woo...
聞こえますか
Can you hear it?
奏で広がる風音
The sound of wind playing and spreading,
手に取り解き放て
take it in your hands and release it.
聞こえますか
Can you hear it?
命始まる脈動
The pulsation where life begins,
愛を突き上げて
thrusting love high.
はるか
Far off,
彼方
beyond,
そして音楽となって過去の
and turning into music, the past...
日は
Days,
風は
winds,
泣いて
crying,
笑い
laughing,
やがて
eventually...
伝え紡ぐ鼓動を歌にした
We turned the conveyed, woven heartbeat into song.
そして夢は開くよ
And so, the dream unfolds
見たことのない世界の果てへ
towards the ends of a world never seen before.
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない
With a light unknown even to God,
ヒカリで歴史を創ろう
let's create history!
不死なる太陽
An immortal sun
未来照らす
illuminating the future!
一緒に飛ばないか
Won't you fly with us?
Just believe 涙で濡れた羽
Just believe, wings soaked in tears,
重くて羽ばたけない日は Wish
On days when they're too heavy to flap... Wish.
その右手に添えよう
Let's place it by that right hand,
描くチカラを
The power to depict...
鳥のように羽ばたき合うよ Singing heart
Like birds, we'll flap our wings together, Singing heart.
いつの日にか分かる時が来るから ずっと
Someday, the time will come when you understand, so always...
忘れない
Don't forget.
その時には 心のあるがままに 笑顔を
When that time comes, smile just as your heart feels.
忘れない
Don't forget.
言葉なんていらない まだ見ぬ地平の先
We don't need words; beyond the unseen horizon,
強く強く手を繋ぎ合おう
Let's join hands strongly.
今 七色の翼 そして生きる今を
Now, rainbow-colored wings, and this moment we live in,
みたことない明日へ
Towards a tomorrow we've never seen before!
Yes, just believe!
1000年後の今日も 生まれ変わって歌いたい
Even 1000 years from now on this day, I want to be reborn and sing.
暖かいよ この温もり
It's warm, this warmth...
絶対離さない
I'll never let it go!
Just believe 運命なんてない
Just believe, there's no such thing as fate!
物語は自分にある
The story lies within ourselves.
逃げ出したくなったら
If you feel like running away,
宇宙を見上げよう
Let's look up at the cosmos!
勇気こそが輝くんだよ Singing star
Courage is what truly shines, Singing star.
遥か星が音楽となったかの日
That day when far-off stars became music,
たぶん 共に出会い 響き
Perhaps together we met and resonated,
神話のひとつのように紡いだ
We spun our tale like a piece of mythology.
何も怖くないよ
There's nothing to be afraid of.
見たことない世界の果てへ
To the end of a world we've never seen before!
Yes, just believe!
神様も知らない
Unknown even to God,
ヒカリで歴史を創ろう
Let's create history with this light!
不死なる太陽 未来照らす
The immortal sun illuminates the future.
一緒に飛ばないか?
Won't you fly with us?
Just believe 涙で濡れた羽
Just believe, wings soaked in tears,
重くて羽ばたけない日は Wish
On days when they're too heavy to flap... Wish.
旋律は溶け合って シンフォニーへと
Melodies melt together into a symphony,
鳥のように羽ばたき合うよ Singing heart
Like birds, we'll flap our wings together, Singing heart.
虹は架かる すべては夢と共に
A rainbow arches over, everything together with our dreams!
野うさぎ剣を押し込め
Push in the Nousagi Sword!
行け 疾風のごとく
Go, like the swift wind,
宿命の剣士よ
O swordsman of destiny!
闇に紛れて
Slip into the darkness...
何故 戦うのか
Why do you fight?
何者か
...who are you...
それは剣に聞け
Ask your sword!
正義だとか 愛など
Things like justice or love...
俺は追いかけない
...I do not pursue.
闇に生まれ 闇に忍び
Born in the darkness, hiding in the darkness,
闇を切り裂く
slashing through the darkness!
遥かな古から
Inherited from far off...
受け継いだ
...ancient times,
使命だから
for it is my mission!
行け！ 疾風のごとく
Go! Like the storming wind,
魔戒の剣士よ
O Makai swordsman!
月満つる夜に
On a full-moon night,
金色になれ
turn to gold!
雄々しき姿の
With your heroic form,
孤独な戦士よ
O lonely warrior!
魂を込めた
Infusing your soul,
怒りの刃 叩きつけて
unleash the blade of wrath!
時代に輝け
Shine in this era,
牙狼！
Garo!
いつの日か お前には
Someday, I want you...
わかってほしい
...to understand...
戦いだけに生きた
...my heart after a life...
俺の胸の内を
...of non-stop fighting.
愛にはぐれ 愛を憎み
Straying from love, hating love,
愛を求める
yet seeking love,
わずかな安らぎさえ
even a moment of peace...
打ち捨てた誓いだけど
...I swore to cast away!
立て！ 修羅のごとく
Stand up! Like the Asura,
魔戒の剣士よ
O Makai swordsman!
運命の歌の
As the song of fate...
命ずるままに
...commands you!
月夜に輝く
Shining in the moonlit night,
孤高の戦士よ
O aloof warrior!
迫り来る影を
The approaching shadows...
一網打尽 叩き斬って
...cut them all down at once!
気高く吠えろ
Howl proudly,
牙狼！
Garo!
行け！ 疾風のごとく
Go! Like the storming wind,
魔戒の剣士よ
O Makai swordsman!
月満つる夜に
On a full-moon night,
金色になれ
turn to gold!
雄々しき姿の
With your heroic form,
孤独な戦士よ
O lonely warrior!
魂を込めた
Infusing your soul,
怒りの刃 叩きつけて
unleash the blade of wrath!
時代に輝け
Shine in this era,
牙狼！
Garo!
行け 疾風のごとく
Go like the wind,
宿命の剣士よ
O swordsman of destiny!
闇に光を
Bring light to the darkness!
警報
[WARNING]
ボーナス、確定
[Bonus Confirmed]
今度こそ 君だけは 幸せにしてみせるぺこ
This time for sure, I'll make you happy, peko.
ボーナス確定
Bonus Confirmed!
これが実力ぺこ！
This is my true power, peko!
悲しい日々が化石に変わるよ もうすぐ
Sad days will soon turn into fossils...
あなたのその痛みを 眠りの森へと ひそやかに導いてあげる
I will secretly lead your pain to the forest of sleep.
おやすみ すべてに 一途すぎた迷い子たち
Good night to all you stray children who were too earnest,
はがゆさが夢に進化する日まで
until the day your impatience evolves into a dream.
生命はまぶしい朝を待っている
Life is waiting for the dazzling morning.
最後の懺悔もかなわないなら
Even if your final confession isn't granted,
いつか時代の夜が明ける
someday the night of this era will break into dawn.
世界よ まぶたを閉じて
World, close your eyes.
生命は目覚めて時を紡ぎだす
Life awakens, weaving time itself,
あなたの証拠をさかのぼるように
as if tracing back the proof of your existence.
そして光が胸に届く
And so, the light reaches your heart.
心よ原始に戻れ
Heart, return to your origin.
涙の岸で ずっとたたずんだ 気持ちを
Standing long on the shore of tears, your feelings...
優しくつつむように 秘密のくすりが 思い出の沖へと運ぶよ
...are gently wrapped as secret medicine carries them to the open sea of memories.
おやすみ モラルに 汚れていた指も耳も
Good night; your fingers and ears dirtied by morality...
この腕の中で もう眠りなさい
...shall now sleep within these arms.
生命はまぶしい朝を待っている
Life is waiting for the dazzling morning.
破れた聖書を抱きしめるより
Rather than clutching torn scriptures,
いつか時代の夜が明ける
someday the night of this era will break into dawn.
あなたよ 祈りを捨てて
You, abandon your prayers.
生命は目覚めて時を紡ぎだす
Life awakens, weaving time itself.
自然の法則にその身をまかせ
Entrust yourself to the laws of nature.
そして光が胸に届く
And so, the light reaches your heart.
心よ原始に戻れ
Heart, return to your origin.
生命はまぶしい朝を待っている
Life is waiting for the dazzling morning.
最後の懺悔もかなわないなら
Even if your final confession isn't granted,
いつか時代の夜が明ける
someday the night of this era will break into dawn.
世界よ まぶたを閉じて
World, close your eyes.
生命は目覚めて時を紡ぎだす
Life awakens, weaving time itself,
あなたの証拠をさかのぼるように
as if tracing back the proof of your existence.
そして光が胸に届く
And so, the light reaches your heart.
心よ原始に戻れ
Heart, return to your origin.
ノエル？
Noel?
フレア？
Flare?
マリン？みんなどこ行っちゃったぺこなのー？
Marine? Where did everyone go, peko?
まあいっか！3期生ならなんとかなるよねきっと！
Well, oh well! I'm sure 3rd Generation will manage somehow!
ということで！
And so!
ここまではたくさんのゲストのみんなと たくさんの曲を歌ってきたぺこが
Up until now, I've sung many songs with lots of guests, peko, but...
ようぺこ！
Yo-peko!
改めまして！
Once again!
楽しんでくれてますか～？
Are you having fun~?
最後にもね、1曲ぺこら、また歌いますので、そちらもお楽しみに！
At the end, Pekora will sing one more song, so look forward to that!
ということで！ここからはグッズ紹介！
And with that! From here on, it's merch presentation!
お、光ったー！
Oh, it lit up!
お？ということは～？
Oh? Which means~?
イイタクセレクト！
It's a great selection!
ということで、兎田ぺこら活動6周年記念グッズを紹介するぺこー！
And so, I'm going to introduce Usada Pekora's 6th Anniversary Commemorative Merch, peko!
まずは1つ目は、こちらかな！トゥルーン！
First up, the 1st item is... this one! Ta-da!
ぺこら推し法被！
Pekora Oshi Happi Coat!
こちらは憂姫はぐれ先生に描いていただきました！
This one was illustrated by Yuhki Hagure-sensei!
もうね、着るだけで推しをアピールできる
Just wearing it lets you show off your oshi,
イベントでも着てきてほしいぺこです！
so I really want you to wear it to events, peko!
めちゃめちゃかわいい法被ぺこなんで、ぜひともよろしくー！
It's a super cute happi coat peko, so please check it out!
そして2つ目は、こちら！トゥルーン！
And the 2nd item is... this! Ta-da!
な、な、なんとついに！ぺこらマミーも写っているグッズが出てしまいました！
W-W-What, finally! Merch featuring Pekora Mommy has been released!
こちら、ラバーマットです！
Here is the Rubber Mat!
イラストはHikosanにお願いしております！
The illustration was drawn by Hikosan!
テーマはカジノの、兎田ぺこらとぺこらマミーです！
The theme is casino, with Usada Pekora and Pekora Mommy!
ついに出てしまったマミーグッズだからね、ぜひともぺこらマミー大好きな人もお手にとってもらえると嬉しいぺこです！
Since Mommy merch has finally been released, I'd be happy if everyone who loves Pekora Mommy gets one too, peko!
そして、ラバーマットがあるということはー？
And if there's a rubber mat, that means...?
3つ目はー、こちらー！
The 3rd item is... this!
はい！カードスリーブもちゃんとあるぺこです！
Yes! There's also card sleeves, peko!
60枚入りでね、イラストは先ほどと同じHikosanにお願いしております！
It comes with 60 sleeves, and the illustration is by Hikosan just like before!
なんとこちら、ホロカでも使えますので、ぜひともホロカで遊んでる方は使っていただけると嬉しいぺこです！
Surprisingly, these can be used in Holoca too, so if you play Holoca, I'd be really happy if you use them, peko!
そして、4つ目はー、こちらー！
And the 4th item is... this!
かわいいね、ぺこらぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
So cute! Pekora Plush Keychain!
カバンにつけてもよし、旅行先に持っていくのもよしな、持ち運びやすいサイズのぬいぐるみとなってるぺこー！
You can attach it to your bag or bring it on trips—it's a plushie in an easy-to-carry size, peko!
こちら、なんとフルセット購入の特典がございます！
Surprisingly, there's a bonus for purchasing the full set!
数量限定で直筆サイン入りポストカードがございます！
In limited quantities, there's a hand-signed postcard!
そしてね、通常バージョンは箔押し複製サイン入りのポストカードとなっておりまして、はぐれ先生の法被のイラストとなっております！
And the regular version comes with a foil-stamped duplicate signature postcard featuring Hagure-sensei's happi coat illustration!
ぜひともジャンジャンバリバリ買ってぺこー！
So please buy, buy, buy, peko~!
それでは、最後は何の曲かな～？お楽しみに～！
Now then, what song will be last~? Look forward to it~!
係員をお呼びください
Please call an attendant.
ちょっと！店員！ライブできない！ライブできない！
Hey! Staff! I can't do the live performance! I can't perform!
直してちょうだい！おい監視カメラ見えてんだろ！どこだ！どこだ！
Fix it, please! Hey, you can see me through the security camera, right?! Where are you?! Where are you?!
直して、早く！ライブできないってどういうことだよ！
Fix it quickly! What do you mean I can't perform?!
叩いて出てもダメぺこでしょ！叩いたって... 蹴っても直らないだろ！ちょっと！
Hitting it won't work, peko! Even if you hit it... kicking it won't fix it! Hey!
仮想の世に生まれ 生きること
Born into a virtual world, to live...
即ち 戦い、勝つこと
Means to fight and win.
時代と戦い
Fight against the era,
己が宿命と戦い
Fight against your destiny,
己自身に打ち勝つ
Overcome yourself.
いつの世も大差はなし
No age is so different.
人の生き様が 一瞬の煌めきが
The way people live, a moment's brilliance,
歴史をつむいでいく
Weaves through history.
今こそ胸に刻め 我が生き様を！
Now engrave in your chest our way of life!
永久に語り継げ 兎田の魂を！
Pass down forever the Usada soul!
戦の炎 灯してみせよ！
Show us the flames of battle burning bright!
Are you ready?
Shall We Dance? 始めよう
Shall We Dance? Let's begin
勝利の祝杯あげる前に
Before raising the victory toast
Relax Your Body 深呼吸
Relax Your Body, take a deep breath
そうすりゃだんだん高まる
Then your passion will gradually rise
Passion Force
Y.U.K.I.M.U.R.A
膝もっと引き上げたら右手あげ YEAH!
Lift your knees higher and raise your right hand, YEAH!
Y.U.K.I.M.U.R.A
◯◯◯◯◯◯ 六文銭
Circle, circle, circle, circle, circle, circle - Six-coin crest!
Y.U.K.I.M.U.R.A
まだいけるはずだもっともっともっともっともっともっと!
You can still keep going! More, more, more, more, more!
Take A Chance! Take A Chance!
勝利のために
For victory!
Well Done!
SANADA DA DANCE
日の本一のつわもの
The greatest warrior in Japan
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA
不惜身命だぜ
Devoting life and soul!
SANADA DA DANCE
急げ夜が明ける前に
Hurry, before dawn breaks!
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA
赤く赤く備えたなら
If you're clad and ready in crimson,
踊れ!歌え!SANADANCE 戦CISE
Dance! Sing! SANADANCE Sen-CISE!
Wow Wow Wow...
(It's Cypher time)
Close your eyes 瞑想
Close your eyes, meditation
Don't think... Feel 感覚研ぎ澄ませたなら高まる
Don't think... Feel! Sharpen your senses to rise higher,
Passion Force
Y.U.K.I.M.U.R.A
フロントキックでツイストかまして視線は下げずにはい、ポーズ!
Front kick, hit a twist, keep your eyes up, and strike a pose!
Y.U.K.I.M.U.R.A
回って回ってブンブン回って回転スピード増し増し
Spin and spin, buzz around, speed up the spin extra fast!
Y.U.K.I.M.U.R.A
勢いつけて!そうだ!もっともっともっともっともっと!
Build up momentum! That's it! More, more, more, more, more!
Change the world! Change the world!
Do or Do not
There is no try
SANADA DA DANCE
ハート燃やして不夜城
Set your heart ablaze in the sleepless night city!
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA
但惜身命だぜ
Cherish your life and soul!
SANADA DA DANCE
心躍らせるために
To make your heart leap with excitement!
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA
熱く熱く構えたなら
If you take position with burning passion,
走れ!回せ!しゃがめ!伸ばせ!
Run! Spin! Crouch! Stretch!
空に叫べ!SANADANCE 戦CISE
Shout to the sky! SANADANCE Sen-CISE!
Wow Wow Wow...
苦しい時や辛い時には身体動かせよ SANADANCE
When times are tough or painful, move your body! SANADANCE!
天上天下 唯我独尊
Above heaven and below earth, I alone am honored!
みんなで踊ろうぜ SANADANCE Let's Go!
Let's all dance together, SANADANCE! Let's Go!
Take A Chance! Change the world!
深呼吸 Ba Hoooooo!
Take a deep breath... Ba Hoooooo!
本日も最終最後の時間まで、兎田ぺこら6周年ライブにお付き合いいただきまして、誠にありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for staying with us until the very end of Usada Pekora's 6th Anniversary Live today.
はい、ありがとうございました。ありがとうございました。
Yes, thank you very much. Thank you very much.
残念ではございますが、間もなく本日のライブはすべて終了とさせていただきます。
Unfortunately, today's live stream will be coming to an end very shortly.
メンバーシップカードをお持ちのお客様にご案内申し上げます。
Here is an announcement for customers with a Membership Card.
メンバーシップカードをお持ちの方は、この後の22時15分より行われるアンコールライブにもご参加いただけます。
If you have a Membership Card, you can also participate in the encore live starting at 22:15.
お持ちでない方もまだ間に合いますので、これを機にぜひご加入ください。
If you don't have one yet, it's not too late, so please take this opportunity to join!
また、グッズ販売の方も間もなくカートオープンとなります。
Also, merchandise sales will be opening in the cart very shortly.
22時10分より販売となりますので、ご購入をご検討の皆様は販売サイトにてご購入ください。
Sales will begin at 22:10, so if you are considering a purchase, please buy from the sales site.
明日のご案内を申し上げます。
Now, an announcement for tomorrow.
明日の営業は通常通り、夜から配信を行います。
Tomorrow's schedule will be business as usual, with a stream starting in the evening.
明日も兎田ぺこら、張り切ってまいりますので、ご来店をお待ちしております。
Usada Pekora will be full of energy tomorrow as well, so we look forward to your visit!
大変名残惜しくはございますが、本日はこれにてライブ終了とさせていただきます。
It is with great regret that we must end the live stream for today.
最終最後までお付き合いいただき、ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much for staying with us until the very end.
USADA PEKORA 周年3DLIVE ぺこらRUSH!!
Usada Pekora Anniversary 3D Live: Pekora RUSH!!